ATANAS KODZHAMANOV

LinkedIn ★ 44 7789 968208 kodzhamanov@gmail.com in LinkedIn GitHub

I have a Master's and Bachelor's degree in Economics and have successfully passed all levels of the CFA exam. I have professional experience in economic analysis and have worked as a SAS/SQL programmer, handling large datasets.

Python, JS, C#, CSS, HTML, SAS, SQL, STATA

PROJECTS

DonaDogs (Django) 2022 - 2023

I collaborated closely with volunteers at a dog shelter to develop and design www.DonaDogs.org, a fully functional charity website built with Django, Python, JavaScript, CSS, and HTML.

Maintaining consistent communication with the charity allowed me to identify and address issues and implement features that aligned with the charity's goals of increased legitimacy and exposure. The impact of website has been significant, with an average of 50 daily visitors and a 6-fold increase in the number of virtual adopters. The website was featured in a Twitch stream aimed at raising funds for the charity and was also named a top 3 winner in a yearly web project competition run by SoftUni.

Working on the project from the ground up provided me with valuable experience in handling various issues such as architecture, design, and dealing with ongoing feature changes.

PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE AND TRAINING

 $\mathbf{SoftUni}$ 2021 – 2023

Software University (SoftUni) is an educational institution that offers a wide range of courses and programs in software development and computer science. I have covered courses in Django, Python, C#, JavaScript and Single Page Applications, HTML and CSS, and am currently enrolled in a React course. All courses are practical and require passing an exam or submitting a final project.

Toulouse School of Economics

2018 - 2020

Completed a course in R programming and applied my skills in R and Stata to manipulate, clean, and analyse data for a final year project as well as various other assignments.

Base 3 Systems 2016

Successfully completed a full-time, intensive training course in SAS and SQL programming, during which I passed several exams and earned two SAS Institute certifications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AlixPartners

2020 - 2023

Economist

London, United Kingdom

- · Responsible for drafting sections of expert reports, conducting market research and literature reviews, performing data analysis, proposing arguments, building econometric models and manipulating data/debugging code in Stata/Python/R.
- · Assisted a leading agricultural supplier in relation to a claim regarding an alleged buyer cartel. Conducted research into past cartels of similar nature and carried out extensive research of the economic theory behind buyer cartels.

- · Supported a major media broadcaster in relation to a dispute in contractual terms renegotiation following Covid-19. Conducted econometric and statistical analysis to predict football game TV viewership using Stata and Tableau.
- · Performed analysis of post-merger competitive effects and foreclosure incentives in the telecommunication sector using a vertical price pressure model.
- · Supported the defence of Visa in relation to the setting of multilateral interchange fees in a damages claim raised by Sainsbury's.
- · Worked with a major car manufacturing company on a damages claim due to a car part cartel. Conducted overcharge pass-on analysis in Stata and built a damages estimation model in Stata and Excel.
- · Assisted a toy manufacturer in an abuse of dominance foreclosure case.

Computershare UK

2016 - 2018

BI Developer

Bingley, United Kingdom

- · Delivered and managed adhoc and regular MI reports for clients across the business using SAS Enterprise Guide, SAS DI Studio, SQL and VBA.
- · Automated and made the production of weekly reports more efficient using Excel VBA.
- · Extensive coding and debugging of SAS and SQL code.
- · Ensured that SQL and SAS code ran as efficiently as possible to accommodate the large datasets handled.

EDUCATION

Toulouse School of Economics

2018 - 2020

M2 in Economics of Markets and Organization (EMO)

Toulouse, France

The programme offered training in Industrial Organization, Game Theory, and Econometrics. In addition to the theoretical knowledge acquired, I also gained practical experience in building a regression model that aims to predict buyer ratings using e-commerce data.

Royal Holloway, University of London

2011 - 2015

BSc Economics

Egham, United Kingdom

Gained a solid foundation in Macroeconomics, Microeconomics, Game Theory and Industrial Organisation.

CERTIFICATIONS

SAS Base Programmer

SAS Advanced Programmer

Passed all levels of CFA